Jordan Allen Foor

jordanallenfoor@gmail.com (765) 480-8408 New York, NY

Web Developer

GitHub LinkedIn Portfolio

Summary

Web Developer who's proficient in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and React framework. I also have eight years of experience in various roles handling project-management within the entertainment industry. I have an interest in design, which ensures that my websites are both aesthetically-pleasing and user-friendly.

Skills

Software Engineering: JavaScript ES6, Node, React, React Hooks, Redux, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, GitHub **Other Skills:** Project-management, visual design, team-collaboration, entertainment

Recent Projects

Local Library | Project Link

- Developed a website for a local neighborhood where users can lend and borrow books, built algorithms based on large datasets in order for users to see which books are available and which ones are currently out
- Built using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript

Decoder Ring | Project Link

- Created an application that encodes and decodes messages
- Built complex algorithms using JavaScript, wrote unit tests with mocha and chai to test the algorithms

Flashcards | Project Link

- Developed an application that allows users to prepare decks of flashcards for self-study
- Wrote react function components, created routes including nested routes using React Router
- Built using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and React

Experience

ENTERTAINMENT CAST MANAGER

Miami, FL

Carnival Cruise Lines

March 2013 – March 2020

- Led a team of performers, ensuring that each stage-show was successful from development to production
- Product-manager of onboard media application for guest-itineraries
- Accomplished goal of becoming number one cast in the company's fleet of ~26 ships
- Nominated and won Team Leader of the Month Award 2019 for providing top-quality entertainment to guests

INAUGURAL PERFORMER

Santa Clarita, CA

Princess Cruises

January 2017 – September 2017

- Performed nightly in newly developed production shows as a dancer, singer, and actor
- Collaborated with creative and development team to create brand new production from start to finish
- Assisted Cast Manager in administrative duties such as leading meetings, scheduling, and instruction

Education

CERTIFICATE, SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

October 2021

Thinkful

• Learned the fundamentals of full stack web development including HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, React.js, Node.js, PostgreSQL, ExpressJS, Data Structures, Algorithms, Git, NPM, and Deployment

BACHELORS, BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION

Arizona State University 2020-PRESENT